# AKINRO NELSON A.

Kilo, Surulere, Lagos State | 09060324100 | nelsonakinro2@gmail.com

### **SUMMARY**

Analytical individual with proficiency in techniques implied for collecting and testing samples, and analysing the results. Competent data management skills that help to update and evaluate geologic data as required for research. Knowledgeable in report development and project management while following procedures and standards. Collaborates effectively with various technical operators, diverse teams and environments. Capable of executing test analysis, production improvement, cost containment, and quality control. Delivers strong leadership abilities while coordinating the activities of geological personnel and interns on geological practices and safety standards on various projects.

## **SKILLS & EXPERTISE**

- Project Management
- Quality Assurance & Control
- Geotechnical Site Investigation
- Microsoft Word
- CSS

- Data Management
- Geological Mapping
- Reporting and Documentation
- Microsoft Excel
- BootStrap

- Geotechnical Field Tests
- Interpersonal Communication
- Organisation & Planning
- HTML
- JavaScript

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Trainee Geologist(NYSC) – MINISTRY OF TRANSPORT AND PETROLEUM RESOURCES, Akwa Ibom State | May 2018 – Mar. 2019 |

- Worked with the geotechnical department in carrying out geological mapping, and also groundwater monitoring.
- Studied and interpreted maps and located places during field trips.
- Determined chemical compositions of tested samples and identified its source.
- Facilitated meetings that includes interactive lessons attended by staff and IT students.
- Lectured IT students on both theoretical and practical aspects of petroleum exploration and exploitation.
- Prepared lecture notes on the basic approaches to petroleum exploration and exploitation.
- Assisted in administrative duties such as filing of documents, record keeping etc.

# Admin Officer – SAMDOC UNIVERSAL COLLEGE, Owo, Ondo State

|Jan. 2017 - Mar. 2018|

- Responsible for overseeing the day-to day operations of the support staff.
- Organized work schedules for non-teaching staff and trained new staffs.
- Supervised the daily activities of six to fifteen employees at a time.
- Made sure all tasks given to staff are done in a timely manner and to the required standard.
- Ensured all documentations were properly filed and maintained.
- Acted as records keeper for both students and staff databases.

### **FIELD WORK**

- Geological Mapping of IGARRA and its environs in Edo State, Nigeria
- Independent Mapping of IDEURE and its environs in Osun State, Nigeria

## **EDUCATION**

 MSc, Petroleum Geology and Sedimentology UNIVERSITY OF IBADAN, Ibadan

Bachelor of Science, Geology
OBAFEMI AWOLOWO UNIVERSITY, Ile-Ife

|2019 - 2020|

|2012 - 2016|